Troy Daniels

Brunswick, VIC troydaniels.me 0450 679 207 troyaadaniels@gmail.com

Software engineer with a keen analytical mindset, and proven work ethic.

My experience includes agile development methodologies, positions of leadership, and liaising with both internal and external stakeholders.

I love all aspects of problem solving, learning, and helping others with the same.

EDUCATION

Graduate Certificate in Information Technology
The University of NSW, Sydney

Dec 2013

Bachelor of Science (Mathematics)
The University of NSW, Sydney

Dec 2010

TECHNOLOGY & SKILL SUMMARY

Programming: JavaScript (ES9+), React, React Native, Vue.js, jQuery, BASH, Java (Core,

Stripes). C

Databases: PostgreSQL **Testing:** Jest, Enzyme, Detox

IDE: JetBrains (IntelliJ, WebStorm, GoLand)

Version Control: Git

Operating Systems: macOS (preferred), Linux, Windows

Other: CCNA (expired)

EMPLOYMENT

Software Engineer

October 2019 - Present

coreplus

South Melbourne, VIC

Team Size: 3 (one of several development teams)

- Upskilling of development team on React/ES best practice, including formalising code style and testing methodologies
- Leading the reimplementation of several legacy Classic ASP projects in React
- Personally involved with each step of SDLC, from customer interviews to product delivery

Lead Front End Engineer

Jul 2017 - October 2019

Vonex Telecom

Richmond, VIC (previously Circular Quay, NSW)

Team Size: 10

- Primary technical liaison between company and ASX listed clients
- Relocated to Melbourne to assist in hiring and training for Melbourne office opening
- Lead the development of the company's new Oper8tor application (available on Google Play and Apple App Stores)
- Conducted all front-end developer interviews, including ad copy & design, initial screening and subsequent face to face assessments

Front End Developer Online Marketing Gurus

Jun 2017 - Nov 2017

Pyrmont, NSW Team Size: 3

- Worked on the implementation of a range of digital search campaigns at varying levels of complexity, in liaising with both our digital marketing team and clients
- Creation of internal tools, as well as dashboards for both internal and external reporting
- Assisted in the introduction, setup, maintenance and staff training across several new software tools and packages

Senior SEO Team Lead Online Marketing Gurus Pyrmont, Sydney

Jan 2016 - June 2017

Team Size: 15

- Worked on the management of a portfolio of digital search campaigns, totally approximately \$100,000 monthly recurring revenue
- Increasingly focused on the automation of various tasks and dashboards through the writing, testing and maintenance of a variety of scripts and proprietary pieces of software

SEO Producer
Web Profits

Sep 2014 – Jan 2016

Chippendale, Sydney

Team Size: 18

- Worked on the management of a portfolio of SEO campaigns, which included the implementation of innovative organic ranking strategies.
- Cross-departmentally, worked on the launch and management of several large digital marketing campaigns, including Profilr, Meriton Serviced Apartments and Tune Hotels (Kuala Lumpur)

MEMBERSHIPS & GROUPS

Australian Mathematical Society